<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<description>The Plaguebearer, a Dread Necromancer subclass by David Adams, from DM's Guild.</description>
		<author url="https://www.dmsguild.com/product/173065/Dread-Necromancer">David Adams</author>
		<update version="1.0">
			<file name="dread-necromancer-plaguebearer.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Saerbhreathach/DNM-aurora/main/dread-necromancer/dread-necromancer-plaguebearer.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Plaguebearer" type="Archetype" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_DREAD_NECROMANCER_PLAGUEBEARER">
		<supports>Dread Calling</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Sinister urges, compulsions to study profane lore, the desire to witness heinous acts - these are the hallmarks of the taint that stains your soul. No dread necromancer can resist them. Some are wholly unable to control this aspect of their behaviour and are drawn to vile subjects they cannot help but learn. Others have some small measure of control over these impulses and delve deep into the darker parts of necromantic knowledge.</p>
			<p>A cough that becomes a fever, which gives way to aches, which leaves behind a putrid corpse. A small scratch that begins to stink, soon to turn green, then black as it spreads. As a <strong>Plaguebearer</strong>, these illnesses are your brethren. The rot within your soul calls out to pestilence and the plagues ripple out from your shadow, leaving only death in your wake.</p>
			<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLAGUEBEARER_FELL_POWER_FESTER" />
			<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLAGUEBEARER_MIASMA_OF_DISEASE" />
			<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLAGUEBEARER_FELL_POWER_SCABROUS_TOUCH" />
			<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLAGUEBEARER_INCITE_AFFLICTION" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>The rot within your soul calls out to pestilence and the plagues ripple out from your shadow, leaving only death in your wake.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLAGUEBEARER_MIASMA_OF_DISEASE" level="6"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLAGUEBEARER_INCITE_AFFLICTION" level="18"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Fell Power: Fester" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLAGUEBEARER_FELL_POWER_FESTER">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_DREAD_NECROMANCER_PLAGUEBEARER_FELL_POWER_FESTER</requirements>
		<supports>Fell Power 7</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 3rd level, you can react to a sudden injury and create a lingering infection that stubbornly resists attempts at healing. Whenever a creature within 30 feet of you takes damage, you can use a reaction to subject them to a festering illness that prevents the triggering damage from being healed by natural or magical means until the wound is thoroughly cleaned and dressed during a short rest, or the effect is ended by a magical ability or spell that can cure disease, such as the <i> lesser restoration</i> spells.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Fester" usage="Reaction">
			<description>Whenever a creature within 30 feet takes damage, you can prevent the damage from healing by natural or magical means until the creature cleans the wound during a short rest, or the effect is ended by a magical ability or spell that can cure disease (eg. Lesser Restoration).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Miasma of Disease" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLAGUEBEARER_MIASMA_OF_DISEASE">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_DREAD_NECROMANCER_PLAGUEBEARER_MIASMA_OF_DISEASE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 6th level, as a reaction you can inflict a disease of your choice upon any creature that ends its turn next to you. Additionally, as a bonus action on your turn, you can deal damage equal to your level to any adjacent creature currently suffering from a disease. The target must also make a Constitution saving throw against a DC 5 + your Charisma modifier + your level. On a failure, the target is poisoned until the end of its next turn. The following are new diseases that can be added to any existing diseases from other sources:</p>
			<p class="indent">
			<span class="feature">Mindfire.</span>Mindfire is an insidious disease feared by wizards everywhere. Once stricken by this ailment, victims suffer periodic delusions that increase in frequency and severity until their sanity is left in tatters. This disease is typically spread by ingesting contaminated brain matter from an afflicted creature, as frequently happens in the creation of dark rituals and vile poultices. Once exposed, the victim has 2d6 hours before the first symptoms manifest. After that time, the victim must make a DC 13 Constitution save. On a failure, the victim experiences periodic flashes of sensory information: sounds and voices, crawling sensations over their skin or from inside their bodies, and flashes of light and figments of visions that aren’t actually present. An afflicted victim cannot maintain concentration on spells and other effects that require dedicated mental focus. Once every 2d20 minutes thereafter, the victim must make another DC 13 Will save. On a failure, they suffer as though under the effects of the spell <i>confusion</i> for one minute. Each time they fail the save, the DC of their next saving throw is increased by 1. On a successful save, the DC resets to 13. After 3d8 days of affliction, the target must make a DC 17 Will save. On a successful save they maintain their sanity for another 24 hours, when they must make the saving throw again. On a failure, the victim is driven mad and suffers from long-term madness (see Chapter 8 of the Dungeon Master’s Guide).<br />
			<span class="feature">Red Ache.</span>Accompanied by fever and severe muscle cramping, red ache is the bane of adventurers everywhere. The disease is not particularly fatal if treated, but the constant body aches caused by this disease make moving difficult and painful. Once exposed, this illness has an incubation period of 2d6 hours before the victim exhibits symptoms. Each hour thereafter, the victim must make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, the victim is struck by intense muscle cramps that cut their speed in half and impose disadvantage on Dexterity saves and ability checks. Should a victim successfully make four consecutive Constitution saves, their body successfully overcomes the infection. A successful DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check also cures the disease.<br />
			<span class="feature">Slimy Doom.</span>Victims of this disease suffer terrible pain as their bodies are slowly liquefied. This frightening disease is typically only encountered in areas fouled by the blood of demons or other evil outsiders. Contact with the contaminant is not enough to catch the disease however. Exposure to open wounds transmits the infection. After 1d4 days of incubation, the symptoms of the disease manifest and the victim suffers occasional vomiting and bloody boils at the site of infection. The victim must then make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw. Success staves off the worst effects of the disease for the next 24 hour s, but the victim deals only half damage with all melee attacks and any Strength or Dexterity save or check is treated as though it were only half of its actual result. Any creature that fails its Constitution saving throw on four consecutive days begins to turn to goo from the inside out. From this point forward the creature is paralyzed and dies within 2d4 days, leaving behind only a wet pile of liquefied viscera. Magic remains the only known way of curing this ailment.<br />
			<span class="feature">The Shakes.</span>The shakes derives its name from the uncontrollable spasms and constant twitching that victims in the grip of the disease exhibit. Typically spread by biting insects breeding in stagnant night soil, the disease is easily curable and noticeably prolific in larger settlements and towns. Once bitten by an insect, the hallmark twitching caused by this disease begins after 1d4 hours. The victim must make a DC 11 Constitution save every hour. On a success, the illness lies dormant for the next hour. Otherwise their twitching is violent enough that they must make a DC 15 Dexterity save every time they pick up or hold an obj ect. On a failure, the object slips through their grasp. There is a 40% chance that the victim is cured naturally of the shakes within 1d4 days. Otherwise, 24 hours of bed rest and a DC 11 Wisdom (Medicine) check cures the illness.<br />
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Reaction - inflict a disease of your choice on any creature that ends its turn next to you.&#13;
			Bonus Action - Deal {{level}} damage to any adjacent creature suffering a disease. The target must make a DC {{miasma:dc}} Constitution save or be Poisoned until the end of its next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="miasma:dc" value="5"/>
			<stat name="miasma:dc" value="charisma:modifier"/>
			<stat name="miasma:dc" value="level"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Fell Power: Scabrous Touch" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLAGUEBEARER_FELL_POWER_SCABROUS_TOUCH">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_DREAD_NECROMANCER_PLAGUEBEARER_FELL_POWER_SCABROUS_TOUCH</requirements>
		<supports>Fell Power 8</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 10th level, you can use your Fell Power to afflict a target that fails the saving throw against your Charnel Touch with a disease of choice. When you do so, the damage dealt by your attack cannot be healed until the disease is cured. You can have only one such disease active at a time.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Scabrous Touch" action="Action">
			<description>When a target fails the saving throw against your Charnel Touch, you may use your Fell Power to afflict them with a disease of your choice. The damage dealt cannot be healed until the disease is cured. You may only have one such disease active at a time.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Incite Affliction" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLAGUEBEARER_INCITE_AFFLICTION">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_DREAD_NECROMANCER_PLAGUEBEARER_INSPIRE_MADNESS</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>At 18th level, you learn to spur the progress of a disease and bring it rapidly to its final, fatal stages. As an action, you cause one creature within 120 feet that you can see to suffer two failed saving throws against your choice of one disease currently afflicting it. The effects of these saving throw failures occur immediately, as they are presented in the description of the disease.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You cause one creature within 120 feet that you can see to suffer two failed saving throws against your choice of one disease currently afflicting it. The effects of these saving throw failures occur immediately, as they are presented in the description of the disease.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
