<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<description>The Fearmonger, a Dread Necromancer subclass by David Adams, from DM's Guild.</description>
		<author url="https://www.dmsguild.com/product/173065/Dread-Necromancer">David Adams</author>
		<update version="1.0">
			<file name="dread-necromancer-fearmonger.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Saerbhreathach/DNM-aurora/main/dread-necromancer/dread-necromancer-fearmonger.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Fearmonger" type="Archetype" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_DREAD_NECROMANCER_FEARMONGER">
		<supports>Dread Calling</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Sinister urges, compulsions to study profane lore, the desire to witness heinous acts - these are the hallmarks of the taint that stains your soul. No dread necromancer can resist them. Some are wholly unable to control this aspect of their behaviour and are drawn to vile subjects they cannot help but learn. Others have some small measure of control over these impulses and delve deep into the darker parts of necromantic knowledge.</p>
			<p>As a <strong>Fearmonger</strong>, the malign power that holds sway over your soul grows hungrier and more feral when mortals cower before you. You become a terrible fiend, wielding fear as a weapon to cut down even the mightiest foe.</p>
			<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEARMONGER_MENACING" />
			<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEARMONGER_FEARSOME_COUNTENANCE" />
			<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEARMONGER_FELL_POWER_THE_BLADE_OF_PAIN_AND_FEAR" />
			<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEARMONGER_INSPIRE_MADNESS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>The malign power that holds sway over your soul grows hungrier and more feral when mortals cower before you.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEARMONGER_MENACING" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEARMONGER_FEARSOME_COUNTENANCE" level="6"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEARMONGER_INSPIRE_MADNESS" level="18"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Menacing" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEARMONGER_MENACING">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_DREAD_NECROMANCER_FEARMONGER_MENACING</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>When you take up this Dread Calling at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with the Intimidate skill and add <i>fear</i> to the list of spells you can cast using Dark Arcana. When you attempt to Intimidate a creature that is frightened, you have advantage on the skill check.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage when attempting to Intimidate a creature that is Frightened.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR" spellcasting="Dread Necromancer" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Fearsome Countenance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEARMONGER_FEARSOME_COUNTENANCE">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_DREAD_NECROMANCER_FEARMONGER_FEARSOME_COUNTENANCE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 6th level, your gaze can inspire overwhelming panic in your foes. As an action, fear radiates outward from your glare. Every living creature that can see you must make a Wisdom saving throw against a DC equal to 8 + your Charisma modifier + your level. On a failure, your targets are frightened and stunned until the end of their next turn. You can concentrate on this power to extend the frightened condition for the duration of your concentration up to a maximum of one hour. Once you have used this ability you must complete a rest before you can use it again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short or Long Rest">
			<description>Every living creature you can see must make a DC {{fearsome countenance:dc}} Wisdom saving throw, or be frightened and stunned until the end of their next turn. You can concentrate on the effect to extend duration up to one hour.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="fearsome countenance:dc" value="8"/>
			<stat name="fearsome countenance:dc" value="charisma:modifier"/>
			<stat name="fearsome countenance:dc" value="level"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Fell Power: The Blade of Pain and Fear" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEARMONGER_FELL_POWER_THE_BLADE_OF_PAIN_AND_FEAR">
		<supports>Fell Power 6</supports>
		<description>
			<p>At 10th level, you can use your Fell Power to turn the fear of your enemies into a weapon to cut them down. As and action, you choose one creature with the frightened 
			condition. Your target becomes exhausted and the frightened condition affecting it ends. At the same time a three-foot-long blade made of twisting darkness, screams, and 
			gnashing teeth appears in your hands. You are proficient with the weapon and can make attacks with it using the greater of your Strength or Dexterity modifier.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon you conjure deals 1d10 slashing damage on a successful hit. As a bonus action, you can steal the fear from another creature that is currently 
			frightened to increase the damage of the Blade of Pain and Fear by 5 points. Creatures whose fear you have stolen become immune to the frightened condition until you 
			dismiss your blade as a bonus action. Once summoned, the Blade of Pain and Fear lasts for one hour. The blade is automatically dismissed if you become unconscious or 
			take a rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="The Blade of Pain and Fear">
			<description>Action: You choose one Frightened creature - it gains one level of exhaustion, and loses the Frightened condition. Once summoned, the Blade of Pain and Fear lasts for one hour. The Blade is automatically dismissed if you become unconscious or take a rest.&#13;
			Bonus Action: Steal fear from a creature that is currently frightened; +5 to The Blade's damage. The creature becomes immune to Frightened until you dismiss The Blade as a bonus action.&#13;
			The Blade of Pain and Fear: Melee Weapon Attack. +{{bopaf:attack}} to hit, 1d10 + {{bopaf:damage}} slashing damage (+5/fear stolen). 
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="bopaf:modifier" value="strength:modifier" bonus="modifier"/>
			<stat name="bopaf:modifier" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="modifier"/>
			<stat name="bopaf:attack" value="proficiency"/>
			<stat name="bopaf:attack" value="bopaf:modifier"/>
			<stat name="bopaf:damage" value="bopaf:modifier"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Inspire Madness" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEARMONGER_INSPIRE_MADNESS">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_DREAD_NECROMANCER_FEARMONGER_INSPIRE_MADNESS</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 18th level, the fear you cultivate in others is powerful enough to drive them mad. As an action you can choose one living creature within 60 feet of you to suffer long-term madness (see Chapter 8 of the Dungeon Master's Guide). The form of madness is randomly determined and can only be cured by a <i>remove curse</i> or <i>wish</i> spell.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You can choose one living creature within 60 feet to suffer long-term madness (see Chapter 8 of the DMG). The effect is randomly determined and only curable by the spells Remove Curse or Wish. </description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
