<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<description>The Corpsecrafter, a Dread Necromancer subclass by David Adams, from DM's Guild.</description>
		<author url="https://www.dmsguild.com/product/173065/Dread-Necromancer">David Adams</author>
		<update version="1.0">
			<file name="dread-necromancer-corpsecrafter.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Saerbhreathach/DNM-aurora/main/dread-necromancer/dread-necromancer-corpsecrafter.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Corpsecrafter" type="Archetype" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_DREAD_NECROMANCER_CORPSECRAFTER">
		<supports>Dread Calling</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Sinister urges, compulsions to study profane lore, the desire to witness heinous acts - these are the hallmarks of the taint that stains your soul. No dread necromancer can resist them. Some are wholly unable to control this aspect of their behaviour and are drawn to vile subjects they cannot help but learn. Others have some small measure of control over these impulses and delve deep into the darker parts of necromantic knowledge.</p>
			<p>As a <strong>Corpsecrafter</strong>, the foul energies that imbue the dead with a vile mockery of life flow unrestrained through you. Your careful attention to the anatomy of the dead and dying gives you profane insight into how to better direct this energy into the dead that you create, bolstering their potency and giving them greater power and endurance.</p>
			<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORPSECRAFTER_FELL_POWER_RESTLESS_DEAD" />
			<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORPSECRAFTER_NECROPOTENT" />
			<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORPSECRAFTER_RAISE_MINION" />
			<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORPSECRAFTER_FELL_POWER_DOMINATE_UNDEAD" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>The foul energies that imbue the dead with a vile mockery of life flow unrestrained through you.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORPSECRAFTER_NECROPOTENT" level="6"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORPSECRAFTER_RAISE_MINION" level="10"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Fell Power: Restless Dead" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORPSECRAFTER_FELL_POWER_RESTLESS_DEAD">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_DREAD_NECROMANCER_CORPSECRAFTER_FELL_POWER_RESTLESS_DEAD</requirements>
		<supports>Fell Power 4</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 3rd level, as an action you can cause a lifeless corpse nearby to strike out at an enemy. Choose one dead body within 30 feet of you that is adjacent to a creature. The corpse makes an unarmed melee attack against an adjacent creature of your choosing using your proficiency bonus. On a hit, the attack deals 1d6 slashing damage for every 3 levels you have in the Dread Necromancer class.</p>
			<p class="indent">Alternatively, you can have the corpse attempt to grapple an adjacent target. Resolve the grapple using the strength score the corpse had in life. This does not allow you to bestow mobility upon the corpse, so you cannot cause the corpse to move the target of your grapple.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Restless Dead" action="Action">
			<description>Choose one dead body within 30 feet of you to make a +{{proficiency}} unarmed melee attack against an adjacent creature. on hit deal {{restless-dead:damage}}d6 slashing damage. &#13;
			Alternatively, you can have the corpse attempt a grapple against its target - it uses the strength it had in life. Even on a hit, it cannot move the target.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="restless-dead:damage" value="1"/>
			<stat name="restless-dead:damage" value="1" level="6"/>
			<stat name="restless-dead:damage" value="1" level="9"/>
			<stat name="restless-dead:damage" value="1" level="12"/>
			<stat name="restless-dead:damage" value="1" level="15"/>
			<stat name="restless-dead:damage" value="1" level="18"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Necropotent" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORPSECRAFTER_NECROPOTENT">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_DREAD_NECROMANCER_CORPSECRAFTER_NECROPOTENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 6th level, you can cast <i>animate dead</i> once per day. You can assert control over two undead creatures with this ability. Undead that you create gain a number of temporary hitpoints equal to your Dread Necromancer level, use your proficiency bonus to make attacks, and have advantage on saving throws to resist being destroyed or controlled by anyone other than you.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can also use your bonus action and expend a use of Fell Power to restore 2d6 hitpoints to any undead creature within 30 feet of you. Additionally, at 12th level, you can assert control over two additional undead creatures with this ability.</p>
			<p class="indent">Further, you add <i>armor of agathys</i>, <i>blur</i>, <i>enahnce ability</i>, and <i>spider climb</i> to the list of spells you can cast with your Dark Arcana. Only undead creatures can be targetted by these spells.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>1/Day: You can cast Animate Dead, asserting control over two undead creatures. They gain +{{level:dread necromancer}} temporary HP, have +{{proficiency}} to attack, and have resistance on saving throws to resist being destroyed or controlled by someone other than you.&#13;
			Bonus Action + Fell Power: You can restore 2d6 HP to any undead creature within 30 feet of you.&#13;
			Armor of Agathys, Blur, Enhance Ability and Spider Climb can only target undead.</description>
			<description level="12">1/Day: You can cast Animate Dead, asserting control over four undead creatures. They gain +{{level:dread necromancer}} temporary HP, have +{{proficiency}} to attack, and have resistance on saving throws to resist being destroyed or controlled by someone other than you.&#13;
			Bonus Action + Fell Power: You can restore 2d6 HP to any undead creature within 30 feet of you.&#13;
			Armor of Agathys, Blur, Enhance Ability and Spider Climb can only target undead.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMOR_OF_AGATHYS" spellcasting="Dread Necromancer" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR" spellcasting="Dread Necromancer" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY" spellcasting="Dread Necromancer" prepared="true" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB" spellcasting="Dread Necromancer" prepared="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Raise Minion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORPSECRAFTER_RAISE_MINION">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_DREAD_NECROMANCER_CORPSECRAFTER_RAISE_MINION</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>At 10th level, you can use your dark craft to create a powerful undead ally to mindlessly serve you. The process takes 24 hours and requires 3,000 gold pieces in material components and a corpse that will serve as the focus of your vile ceremony and unspeakable preparations. The 24 hours need not be consecutive, but you must spend at least 4 hours a day working on your minion. If you fail to do so, your components are spoiled, and you must begin the ritual anew.</p>
			<p class="indent">At the end of the process, your undead minion animates. Your minion is mindless, but can act somewhat independently, should your instructions be detailed enough. Unless told to do otherwise, your minion will attempt to follow you and remain within 10 feet. The minion becomes inert if separated from you by more than 200 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you create your minion, you may animate the corpse you use as either a skeleton or zombie of CR 1/4 or lower. Add your proficiency to the creature's AC, attack rolls, and damage rolls. The creature's hitpoint maximum becomes four times your Dread Necromancer level and it gains 1d12 hitdie for every two levels of Dread Necromancer you possess, which it can spend during a short rest or as an action ot recover hitpoints in combat. It regains these hitpoints once it has completed a long rest. Your minion is also proficient with light, medium and heavy armors and melee martial weapons and shields. </p>
			<p class="indent">During combat you may use an action during your turn to command your undead minion to undertake any activity that it could reasonably accomplish; your commands allow the minion to move up to its speed and take a single action. As part of this action you may also simultaneously issue commands to any undead you control with your Necropotent ability. When you issue a command to attack, your minion can make two melee attacks as part of the attack action. If you command your minion to defend you, any creature making a melee attack against you has disadvantage and your minion gains one reaction that it can use to make a melee attack against a creature within its reach that attempts to attack you. Your minion lacks the intelligence to activate magic items, but can benefit from any effects of worn magic items that do not require attunement or activation. If you do not issue a command during combat, there is a 20% chance your minion will move towards and attack the nearest living creature other than yourself. Otherwise it clumsily moves up to 15 feet closer to you.</p>
			<p class="indent">Outside of combat, your minion follows close to you and waits for your instructions to act. If your minion is ever destroyed, you may conduct this ritual again to raise a new minion. You can only have one minion at a given time.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_INFORMATION_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_SKELETON" />
				<div element="ID_DMSG_DADN_INFORMATION_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_ZOMBIE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can take 24 hours and 3,000 gold pieces in material components and a corpse to create a powerful undead ally that will mindlessly serve you. You must spend at least 4 hours each day until the 24 hours have been completed working on your minion, or the components are spoiled and the ritual begun again.&#13;
			With the process complete, your minion animates, and can act somewhat independently, or follow your instructions if detailed enough. Unless told to do otherwise, your minion will attempt to follow you and remain within 10 feet, becoming inert if more than 200 feet from you.&#13;
			Outside of combat, your minion follows close to you and waits for your instructions to act. If your minion is ever destroyed, you may conduct this ritual again to raise a new minion. You can only have one minion at a given time.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Companion" name="Corpsecrafter Minion" supports="Corpsecrafter Minion" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Fell Power: Dominate Undead" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORPSECRAFTER_FELL_POWER_DOMINATE_UNDEAD">
		<requirements>!ID_INTERNAL_FEATURE_REPLACEMENT_DREAD_NECROMANCER_CORPSECRAFTER_DOMINATE_UNDEAD</requirements>
		<supports>Fell Power 5</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 18th level you can use an action to gain absolute control over nearby undead creatures. Choose any number of undead creatures within 60 feet whose total CR is less than your Dread Necromancer level. These targets must make a Constitution saving throw or be charmed by you as if you had cast the <i>dominate beast</i> spell on it.</p>
			<p class="indent">As long as you maintain concentration on this effect, you retain control on your targets for up to four hours. Intelligent undead have advantage on saving throws to resist or break free of this ability and any undead creature that is successful at the saving throw cannot be targeted by this ability for 24 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Dominate Undead" action="Action">
			<description>Choose any number of undead within 60 feet whose total CR is less than {{level:dread necromancer}}. Targets make a DC {{dominate:dc}} Constitution saving throw or be charmed as the Dominate Beast spell, for up to 4 hours, as long as you maintain concentration. Intelligent undead have advantage on saving throws to resist or break free of this ability, and any creature that succeeds on their save cannot be targeted for 24 hours.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dominate:dc" value="8"/>
			<stat name="dominate:dc" value="proficiency"/>
			<stat name="dominate:dc" value="charisma:modifier"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!--Companion-->
	<element name="Corpsecrafter Minion: Skeleton" type="Companion" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_DREAD_NECROMANCER_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_SKELETON">
		<supports>Corpsecrafter Minion</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have used your dark craft to create a powerful undead ally to mindlessly serve you.</p>
			<p><b>Proficiency Bonus (PB)</b> equals your bonus</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="size">Medium</set>
			<set name="type">Undead</set>
			<set name="alignment">neutral</set>
			<set name="ac">13 (armor scraps) plus PB</set>
			<set name="hp">Four times your dread necromancer level (the minion has a number of Hit Dice [d12s] equal to half your dread necromancer level)</set>
			<set name="speed">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="strength">10</set>
			<set name="dexterity">14</set>
			<set name="constitution">15</set>
			<set name="intelligence">6</set>
			<set name="wisdom">8</set>
			<set name="charisma">5</set>
			<set name="vulnerabilities">bludgeoning</set>
			<set name="immunities">poison</set>
			<set name="conditionImmunities">exhaustion, poisoned</set>
			<set name="senses">darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 9</set>
			<set name="languages">understands the languages it knew in life</set>
			<set name="challenge">1/4</set>
			<set name="traits">ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_PROFICIENCIES,ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_ACTION,ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_MAGIC_ITEMS,ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_AUTONOMY</set>
			<set name="actions">ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_ACTION_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_MULTIATTACK</set>
			<set name="reactions">ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_REACTION_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_DEFEND</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="13"/>
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:dread necromancer" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:dread necromancer" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:dread necromancer" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:dread necromancer" />
			<stat name="companion:speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:proficiency" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:proficiency" value="-2" bonus="base companion PB removal"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Corpsecrafter Minion: Zombie" type="Companion" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_DREAD_NECROMANCER_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_ZOMBIE">
		<supports>Corpsecrafter Minion</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have used your dark craft to create a powerful undead ally to mindlessly serve you.</p>
			<p><b>Proficiency Bonus (PB)</b> equals your bonus</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="size">Medium</set>
			<set name="type">Undead</set>
			<set name="alignment">neutral</set>
			<set name="ac">8 plus PB</set>
			<set name="hp">Four times your dread necromancer level (the minion has a number of Hit Dice [d12s] equal to half your dread necromancer level)</set>
			<set name="speed">20 ft.</set>
			<set name="strength">13</set>
			<set name="dexterity">6</set>
			<set name="constitution">16</set>
			<set name="intelligence">3</set>
			<set name="wisdom">6</set>
			<set name="charisma">5</set>
			<set name="immunities">poison</set>
			<set name="conditionImmunities">poisoned</set>
			<set name="senses">darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 8</set>
			<set name="languages">understands the languages it knew in life</set>
			<set name="challenge">1/4</set>
			<set name="traits">ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_PROFICIENCIES,ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_ACTION,ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_MAGIC_ITEMS,ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_AUTONOMY,ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_UNDEAD_FORTITUDE</set>
			<set name="actions">ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_ACTION_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_MULTIATTACK</set>
			<set name="reactions">ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_REACTION_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_DEFEND</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="13"/>
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="proficiency"/>
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:dread necromancer" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:dread necromancer" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:dread necromancer" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:dread necromancer" />
			<stat name="companion:speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:proficiency" value="proficiency"/>
			<stat name="companion:proficiency" value="-2" bonus="base companion PB removal"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Proficiences" type="Companion Trait" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_PROFICIENCIES">
		<description>
			<p>Your minion is proficient with light, medium and heavy armors and melee martial weapons and shields.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your minion is also proficient with light, medium and heavy armors and melee martial weapons and shields.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELD" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Actions" type="Companion Trait" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_ACTION">
		<description>
			<p>During combat you may use an action during your turn to command your undead minion to undertake any activity that it could reasonably accomplish; your commands allow the minion to move up to its speed and take a single action. As part of this action you may also simultaneously issue commands to any undead you control with your Necropotent ability.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You may use an action during your turn to command your undead minion (and any you control with Necropotent) to undertake any activity that it could reasonably accomplish; your commands allow the minion to move up to its speed and take a single action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Magic Items" type="Companion Trait" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_MAGIC_ITEMS">
		<description>
			<p>Your minion lacks the intelligence to activate magic items, but can benefit from any effects of worn magic items that do not require attunement or activation.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your minion lacks the intelligence to activate magic items, but can benefit from worn magic items that do not require attunement or activation.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Autonomy" type="Companion Trait" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_AUTONOMY">
		<description>
			<p>If you do not issue a command during combat, there is a 20% chance your minion will move towards and attack the nearest living creature other than yourself. Otherwise it clumsily moves up to 15 feet closer to you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Without a command during combat, there is a 20% chance your minion will move towards and attack the nearest living creature other than yourself. Otherwise it clumsily moves up to 15 feet closer to you.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Undead Fortitude" type="Companion Trait" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_TRAIT_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_UNDEAD_FORTITUDE">
		<description>
			<p>If damage reduces the zombie to 0 hit points, it must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC of 5 + the damage taken, unless the damage is radiant or from a critical hit. On a success, the zombie drops to 1 hit point instead.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>If your minion is reduced to 0 HP, make a Constitution saving throw of DC 5 + the damage taken, unless radiant or a critical hit. On success, drop to 1 HP instead.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Multiattack" type="Companion Action" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_ACTION_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_MULTIATTACK">
		<description>
			<p>When you issue a command to attack, your minion can make two melee attacks as part of the attack action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>On your command, your minion makes two attacks adding +{{multiattack}} to both its attacks and damage with the weapon it is holding.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="multiattack" value="proficiency"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Defend" type="Companion Reaction" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_COMPANION_REACTION_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_DEFEND">
		<description>
			<p>If you command your minion to defend you, any creature making a melee attack against you has disadvantage and your minion gains one reaction that it can use to make a melee attack against a creature within its reach that attempts to attack you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>If you command your minion to defend you, melee attacks against you are at disadvantage&#13;
			Your minion can use its reaction to make one melee attack against an attacker in range.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Corpsecrafter Minion: Skeleton" type="Information" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_INFORMATION_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_SKELETON">
		<description>
			<p style="margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Medium undead</em></p>
			<h4 style="margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 13 (armor scraps) + PB</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> four times your dread necromancer level (the minion has a number of Hit Dice [d12s] equal to half your dread necromancer level)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30 ft.</li>
			</ul>
			<table style="text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>10 (+0)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>15 (+2)</td><td>6 (-2)</td><td>8 (-1)</td><td>5 (-3)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Damage Vulnerabilities</strong> bludgeoning</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> exhaustion, poisoned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 9</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> understands the languages it spoke in life</li>
				<li style="margin-bottom:-1em"><strong>Challenge</strong> 1/4</li>
				<li style="text-align:right; margin-top:-1em"><strong>Proficiency Bonus (PB)</strong> equals your bonus</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style="margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Proficiencies.</em></strong> Your minion is proficient with light, medium and heavy armors and melee martial weapons and shields.</li>
				<li><strong><em>Actions.</em></strong> You may use an action during your turn to command your undead minion (and any you control with Necropotent) to undertake any activity that it could reasonably accomplish; your commands allow the minion to move up to its speed and take a single action.</li>
				<li><strong><em>Magic Items.</em></strong> Your minion lacks the intelligence to activate magic items, but can benefit from worn magic items that do not require attunement or activation.</li>
				<li><strong><em>Autonomy.</em></strong> Without a command during combat, there is a 20% chance your minion will move towards and attack the nearest living creature other than yourself. Otherwise it clumsily moves up to 15 feet closer to you.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style="margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> On your command, your minion makes two attacks adding your PB to both its attacks and damage with the weapon it is holding.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style="margin-top:10px">Reactions</h4>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Defend.</em></strong> If you command your minion to defend you, melee attacks against you are at disadvantage. Your minion can use its reaction to make one melee attack against an attacker in range.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
	</element>

	<element name="Corpsecrafter Minion: Zombie" type="Information" source="Dread Necromancer" id="ID_DMSG_DADN_INFORMATION_CORPSECRAFTER_MINION_ZOMBIE">
		<description>
			<p style="margin-bottom:-5px"><em>Medium undead</em></p>
			<h4 style="margin-top:5px" />
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 8 + PB</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong> four times your dread necromancer level (the minion has a number of Hit Dice [d12s] equal to half your dread necromancer level)</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 20 ft.</li>
			</ul>
			<table style="text-align:center;margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px">
				<thead><tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>13 (+1)</td><td>6 (-2)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>3 (-4)</td><td>6 (-2)</td><td>5 (-3)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws</strong> Wis +0 plus PB</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> poisoned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 8</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> understands the languages it spoke in life</li>
				<li style="margin-bottom:-1em"><strong>Challenge</strong> 1/4</li>
				<li style="text-align:right; margin-top:-1em"><strong>Proficiency Bonus (PB)</strong> equals your bonus</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style="margin-top:5px; margin-bottom:10px" />
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Proficiencies.</em></strong> Your minion is proficient with light, medium and heavy armors and melee martial weapons and shields.</li>
				<li><strong><em>Actions.</em></strong> You may use an action during your turn to command your undead minion (and any you control with Necropotent) to undertake any activity that it could reasonably accomplish; your commands allow the minion to move up to its speed and take a single action.</li>
				<li><strong><em>Magic Items.</em></strong> Your minion lacks the intelligence to activate magic items, but can benefit from worn magic items that do not require attunement or activation.</li>
				<li><strong><em>Autonomy.</em></strong> Without a command during combat, there is a 20% chance your minion will move towards and attack the nearest living creature other than yourself. Otherwise it clumsily moves up to 15 feet closer to you.</li>
				<li><strong><em>Undead Fortitude.</em></strong> If your minion is reduced to 0 HP, make a Constitution saving throw of DC 5 + the damage taken, unless radiant or a critical hit. On success, drop to 1 HP instead.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style="margin-top:10px">Actions</h4>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> On your command, your minion makes two attacks adding your PB to both its attacks and damage with the weapon it is holding.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4 style="margin-top:10px">Reactions</h4>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong><em>Defend.</em></strong> If you command your minion to defend you, melee attacks against you are at disadvantage. Your minion can use its reaction to make one melee attack against an attacker in range.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
	</element>
</elements>
